<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Enrique Comba Riepenhausen</title>
 <link href="http://ecomba.pro/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://ecomba.pro/"/>
 <updated>2015-04-01T22:21:58+01:00</updated>
 <id>http://ecomba.pro</id>
 <author>
   <name>Enrique Comba Riepenhausen</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Curiosity</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2015/04/01/curiosity/"/>
   <updated>2015-04-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2015/04/01/curiosity</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is much pleasure to be gained from useless knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Bertrand Russell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you find yourself, sometimes, reading or researching some seemingly pointless piece of information? Have you ever gone on a limb to find out something more about some random fact that you have overheard?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or, on the other hand, do you frown upon people who do these kind of things? Do you think these are pointless exercises that are a waste of everyones time?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Useless knowledge&lt;/em&gt; helps you to feed your curiosity and your ability to find information just about any topic you can imagine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a knowledge worker, a problem solver by profession, this is an excellent way to hone your skills; because &lt;em&gt;useless knowledge&lt;/em&gt; is not so useless after all.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Craziness</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/31/craziness/"/>
   <updated>2015-03-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/31/craziness</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Why do so many people work so hard so they can escape to Disneyland? Why are video games more popular than work? … Why do many workers spend years dreaming about and planning for retirement?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason is simple and dispiriting. We have made the workplace a frustrating and joyless place where people do what they’re told and have few ways to participate in decisions or fully use their talents. As a result, they naturally gravitate to pursuits in which they can exercise a measure of control over their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In most organisations I have been exposed to around the world, … we still have the offices “above” the working people … who, without consulting workers, make decisions that dramatically affect their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Dennis Bakke&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop playing video games to escape your reality! Stop trying to control the little things that don’t really count to much in your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are exceptional and incredibly capable of doing what you should be doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things need to change, &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;we need to regain control of our &lt;em&gt;self&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Breaking the chain</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/30/breaking-the-chain/"/>
   <updated>2015-03-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/30/breaking-the-chain</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man was born free, and he is everywhere in chains&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Jean-Jacques Rousseau&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are chains in our society, in the pressure of living in a society. Some of them can be broken with courage and determination, some are harder to go through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breaking free of chains requires courage. The smallest chain, made of the weakest material can seem daunting at first. What is an impossible task at first might be really easy to master once you can see past your own anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your chains can be broken – &lt;em&gt;only if you will&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Anger</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/29/anger/"/>
   <updated>2015-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/29/anger</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anybody can become angry – that is easy, but to be angry
with the right person and to the right degree and at the
right time and for the right purpose, and in the right way –
that is not within everybody’s power and is not easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Aristotle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Curiosity drives the minds of the human nature. We seek and seek to understand. Sometimes we ask questions when we don’t understand something, sometimes we show the world what we have found or what we have – within the limits of our own perception – witnessed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the rise of the &lt;em&gt;Social Media&lt;/em&gt; this has been multiplied to a great extent. What someone said in one remote corner of the world is oftentimes discussed in a complete different corner of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It incredible beautiful and empowering how we can make our world shrink and bring us all together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly though, this is not the only thing happening. Every comment is directed, every opinion turned over. The curious get shot down with angry comments, the opinions of others assaulted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The web we have created is turning into an hostile place to be in. There is a lot of anger in the world. I am no one to tell you to change, but next time you want to give an off response to someone try to sit back, think again about the context and relax a moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There is no need to be insulting strangers all over the world just because they are not standing in front of you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Seed</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/28/seed/"/>
   <updated>2015-03-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/28/seed</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think twice before you speak, because your words and influence 
will plant the seed of either success of failure in the mind
of another&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Napoleon Hill&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your mind can be influenced very easily – words we say to others can prime them to fail or do great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It’s quite remarkable how we are wired.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next time you feel a certain way (&lt;em&gt;anxious, amazing, etc&lt;/em&gt;) spend some time thinking why that is. Did you or someone else say something that made you feel that way?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is power in words, use them wisely!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Trust</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/27/trust/"/>
   <updated>2015-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/27/trust</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust is the glue of life. It&amp;#39;s the most essential ingredient
in effective communication. It&amp;#39;s the foundational principle
that holds all relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Stephen Covey&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you trust the people you work with?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t just go and and answer &lt;em&gt;”yes”&lt;/em&gt;. Think about it first. And besides, no one is going to hear your answer anyways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does it mean to &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; trust someone?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are the people you know that will do anything in their hands to help you with whatever problem you have; they are rare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the work environment you will possibly not achieve this level of trust I am talking about, but you will definitely know if you don’t trust someone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t trust the people you work with find someone you do trust – you will enjoy work and your life far more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trust me on that!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Open your eyes</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/26/open-your-eyes/"/>
   <updated>2015-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/26/open-your-eyes</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ultimate value of life depends upon awareness and the power of contemplation rather than upon mere survival.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Aristotle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zombies walk our streets day in and day out. People with their heads buried in their mobile phones, day dreaming or simply just sleeping whilst they are walking to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It shocks me every time when I come to this realisation as I dodge people on the streets…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are not aware of your surroundings, you live inside your on shell disregarding anyone and everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If everyone would try to be a little more aware and try not to step on every others toes (&lt;em&gt;figuratively and not so figuratively&lt;/em&gt;) everything would be so much better for all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Human, please be HUMAN!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>At ease</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/25/at-ease/"/>
   <updated>2015-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/25/at-ease</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being at ease with not knowing is crucial for answers to come
to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Eckhart Tolle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being at ease is easier said than done. It’s the feeling of feeling comfortable in your own skin; no matter where you are (&lt;em&gt;work, with friends, etc&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s something so simple and yet so difficult to achieve, there are people we feel we need to please, the social pressure…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question is, &lt;strong&gt;why do you think you have to please anyone?&lt;/strong&gt; The only person that really matters in your life is &lt;strong&gt;you&lt;/strong&gt;. You have to live with yourself for the rest of your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being at ease, finding comfort in who you are, is possibly the first (&lt;em&gt;and possibly only&lt;/em&gt;) step you should take in your daily interaction with people.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Focus</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/24/focus/"/>
   <updated>2015-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/24/focus</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;People like the late Steve Jobs where known for their incredible ability to develop a laser sharp focus when it came to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mastery in a skill takes a lifetime of dedication and perfection. You need to practice day in and day out honing the skill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem comes when the skill you practice is the only thing you practice. As a developer you need to hone a whole array of skills ranging from a notion of design, business, marketing, human empathy, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coding, alas the one you will focus the most in, should not be your only skill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your focus should lie on being an all-round better person.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Companies</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/23/companies/"/>
   <updated>2015-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/23/companies</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The way we perceive companies from the outside varies. Most look like a thing, a faceless corporation that offers a product or a service – &lt;em&gt;a tribe&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How the company is perceived within; that’s a more interesting question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly I see a lot of places in where people are completely disengaged by their work or company. They are there because it pays the bills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other companies there is the will to do meaningful work, but somehow “&lt;em&gt;the company&lt;/em&gt;” is making it hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either way, that concept of a company, in the smaller scale, is obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You should strive to work in a place that gives your work meaning, a place where you can express yourself!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Challenge</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/22/challenge/"/>
   <updated>2015-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/22/challenge</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you only do it when you feel like it, it’s hardly a 
challenge. Everyone can do that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Chloë Donegan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stepping out of your comfort zone to grow is not an easy thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stevenpressfield.com/the-war-of-art/&quot;&gt;The Resistance&lt;/a&gt; will pull hard against every attempt to face a new challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What you need to realise how to use &lt;em&gt;the resistance&lt;/em&gt; as a reverse compass. The more you feel repelled by that challenge you have setup to do, the more you should face it and do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What helps you overcoming the resistance to face you hardest challenges?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Helping</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/21/helping/"/>
   <updated>2015-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/21/helping</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one is useless in this world who lightens the burdens of another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Charles Dickens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How would you define happiness? Can you imagine the most happy day in your life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might look something like this. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You wake up in the morning energised. You go for a run with your partner and then, after a romantic shower together you have a beautiful breakfast. Then you go out to some nice market to find nice new things or pursue a hobby followed by great food and other pleasantries of life.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some would say a day like that (&lt;em&gt;or a variation of that&lt;/em&gt;) would be a happy day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the day could equally look more like a hard grind as you are trying to help people in need, sweating, cursing, getting dirty as you do your best to make the lives of others better. At the end of that day you’d feel a sense of accomplishment that would make you feel happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love helping others. It makes me happy to see that I could better the life of someone (&lt;em&gt;even if it’s just a marginal betterment&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When was the last time you did help someone even though you could have done something different that day?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Experience</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/20/experience/"/>
   <updated>2015-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/20/experience</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not think, sir, you have any right to command me, merely
because you are older than I, or because you have seen more of
the world than I have; your claim to superiority depends on
the use you have made of your time and experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Charlotte Brontë, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Jane-Wordsworth-Classics-Charlotte-Bront%C3%AB/dp/1853260207/ref=pd_bxgy_b_text_y&quot;&gt;Jane Eyre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I love the world we are living in!&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was younger people were judged (&lt;em&gt;and got their great reputation&lt;/em&gt;) by their titles and what they had studied. If you had a doctor title, were a professor or anything alike &lt;strong&gt;you were someone&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world has changed though. A title proves you knew how to pass a test; you mastered the ability to keep your head down and to all the things needed to earn it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are judged by the value they bring to others, by what they do and how they are able to make the lives of others better than they were before they met.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are what you can do, not who you say you are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What can &lt;strong&gt;you&lt;/strong&gt; do? How will you &lt;strong&gt;improve my life&lt;/strong&gt; if we meet?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Silence</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/19/silence/"/>
   <updated>2015-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/19/silence</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the End, we will remember not the words of our enemies, but the silence of our friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Martin Luther King, Jr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The city is loud. There is an incessant cacophony all around us; the soundtrack of our metropolitan lives. Some of us cover the sound with yet more sound – silence, &lt;strong&gt;where is it gone?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Today when I woke up I decided not to open my eyes at first. I was just letting my senses discover my surroundings. First the sounds of the busy street I live in outside of my bedroom, the warm embrace of my duvet and finally the light shining through the window blind.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I miss the silence, not the total absence of sound, but the sound of nature; far away from the madness of a city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When was the last time you experienced a whole day of silence?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Patience</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/18/patience/"/>
   <updated>2015-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/18/patience</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patience is not simply the ability to wait – it’s how we behave while we are waiting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Joice Meyer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes things don’t happen the way, or rather at the pace we want them to happen. Things move slower than (&lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt;) expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How are you going to react in that situation? Are you going to be the one who shouts, gets restless and insulting? Or are you going to be the one who relaxes and takes a look at the situation and tries to make the best out of it given the circumstances?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way you feel, your attitude to challenging situations, is your choice; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;who are you going to be today?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Autenticity</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/17/authenticity/"/>
   <updated>2015-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/17/authenticity</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Authenticity is ones degree to which you are true to your own personality despite external pressures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I asked you right now if you are authentic every single time of your life, chances are you will tell me something in the lines of &lt;em&gt;”but of course I am!”&lt;/em&gt;. And in your case it might well be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More often than not we give in to the social pressure and are what we are expected to be by others. When we meet people who are authentic there is this sense of completeness about them, they somehow seem to be more real than the rest of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For one day, one day only try to be who you really are.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And when that day is over, write about your experience as yourself &amp;trade; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Laughter</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/16/laughter/"/>
   <updated>2015-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/16/laughter</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laughter is the sun that drives the winter from the human face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Victor Hugo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When was the last time you laughed at work? The last time you felt you are having a really good time as you work through your tasks?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s surprising how many people struggle to find joy whilst working. Yes, sometimes we do things we do not like, work at jobs that we’d rather not do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still challenge you, even if you don’t like what you are currently doing, to find a little joy in it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>To Care</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/14/care/"/>
   <updated>2015-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/14/care</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When people talk about what they do in the software development field they talk about &lt;em&gt;best practices, clean code, engineering, etc&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All these things are absolutely great if you think about them, but there is something else, something that we introduced when we started the &lt;a href=&quot;http://manifesto.softwarecraftsmanship.org&quot; title=&quot;Software Craftsmanship Movement&quot;&gt;Software Craftsmanship movement&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;care&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you &lt;em&gt;care&lt;/em&gt; about what you do, you not only use the best of your ability as you work, you transmit a little of yourself into your work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The products, services and software you build become part of what you are, they get imprinted with your &lt;em&gt;DNA&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are not many people who do work like this, it’s still very rare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do you &lt;strong&gt;really care&lt;/strong&gt; about your work?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Dilution |dʌɪˈluːʃn|</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/13/dilution/"/>
   <updated>2015-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/13/dilution</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;noun [ mass noun ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the action of making a liquid more dilute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; the action of making something weaker in force, content, or value&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; [ count noun ] a liquid that has been diluted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; [ count noun ] the degree to which a solution has been diluted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; a reduction in the value of a shareholding due to the issue of additional shares in a company without an increase in assets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ &lt;em&gt;Oxford Dictionary of English&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We see it over and over – A nice burger joint opens, they serve delicious food.
Someone down the line decides it&amp;#39;s time to reduce costs by diluting the 
ingredients, using cheaper products, etc. You still go there; for a while.
Eventually though you decide it&amp;#39;s time to move on and try that other place out...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sadly this is commonplace in businesses frozen in past practices.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want to have a service, product, company that your customers will love?
The trick is pretty simple...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Never ever insult them by reducing the quality of what you once were!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Communication</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/12/communication/"/>
   <updated>2015-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/12/communication</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A wonderful fact to reflect upon, that every human creature is constituted
to be that profound secret and  mystery to every other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Charles Dickens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communicating with other people is sometimes so difficult, there are things
we want to tell them, but we feel that they might take it the &lt;em&gt;wrong&lt;/em&gt; way.
So we decide not to speak up, not to tell our team, customer, friend
something that might hurt them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inevitably those relations start to suffer as communication breaks down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenges of developing software are mostly unrelated to technology.
Projects, ideas, enterprises rise and fall due to the ability of their people
to communicate with each other, to pursue a common goal and to ultimately
succeed at what they do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make an effort and try to communicate with your team, be polite, but do not
leave words unspoken.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Success</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/11/success/"/>
   <updated>2015-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2015/03/11/success</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you define success?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people think of success in terms of monetary rewards (&lt;em&gt;accumulation
of wealth&lt;/em&gt;), others in how wellknown they or their venture is (&lt;em&gt;there are
many other definitions, which I am not going to go into&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of these definitions ever struck a chord with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;d like to define successful people as those who get a great satisfaction of
what they do everyday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you there? Do you get that tingling sensation every day before you start?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What can you do to get there? Can I help you?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>FDD - Fun Driven Development</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2014/12/03/fun-driven-development/"/>
   <updated>2014-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2014/12/03/fun-driven-development</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Laughing and having a good time is known to help in working and getting 
things done better; to be more productive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is something I take at heart a lot. I have been called &lt;em&gt;child&lt;/em&gt; by some 
very serious developers (serious as in not smiling much) or looked at in 
sheer astonishment with the question &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;you guys are really working?&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way I work best, when my code is the cleanest, when I give the best business advice is when I am having fun. The lightheartedness of my spirit makes me grow and come up with a myriad of ideas and solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How are you at your best?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;small&gt;This post appeared first in March 2012 on my pervious blog at &lt;strong&gt;ecomba.org&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Crossroads</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2014/12/01/crossroads/"/>
   <updated>2014-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2014/12/01/crossroads</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wherever you go becomes a part of you somehow
-- Anita Desai&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I decided that It was time
for me to move on from &lt;a href=&quot;http://makersacademy.com&quot;&gt;Makers Academy&lt;/a&gt; and
continue my journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working at &lt;a href=&quot;http://makersacademy.com&quot;&gt;Makers Academy&lt;/a&gt; has been a great
experience. I met really wonderful people and new friends. The feeling and
pride of helping people to learn how to code has been great; &lt;strong&gt;my heart will
always have this warm feeling about my time there&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time of writing I am still unsure what to do, there are some amazing
offers on the table, some crazy ideas and a ton of uncertainty. My decision 
at the moment is not to decide on anything. I am spending the month of
December in a sort-of-sabbatical where I will try not to think about anything
concrete (&lt;em&gt;this is proving difficult as my brain is finding idea after idea
at the moment&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am in that figurative crossroads looking into the different paths thinking
to myself: &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Which one of these has dragons and which one will lead me a 
little closer to mastery?&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any idea of what I should do, let me know, I am all ears for any
proposal (&lt;em&gt;not deciding yet though&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, one last thing, regardless of the decision I have created a newsletter:
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyletter.com/ecomba&quot;&gt;Enrique&amp;#39;s week in a bottle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;you can
also find a link on the sidebar&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>How it all starts</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2014/08/31/in-the-beginning/"/>
   <updated>2014-08-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2014/08/31/in-the-beginning</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I had the idea for &lt;a href=&quot;http://patheleven.com&quot;&gt;patheleven&lt;/a&gt; I wanted to bring
together a great team of people that wanted to grow and help other people
grow together. The main goal was to change the way we work and interact
with our customers and our surroundings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During our time we learned a lot of valuable lessons and we learned what we
did and didn&amp;#39;t want from a company; &lt;strong&gt;it was a great adventure&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you know, we all disbanded and went our own ways to enjoy doing what we
like doing, but also to have a break from what we did with 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://patheleven.com&quot;&gt;patheleven&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a small boutique software development shop is a really tough business,
 &lt;em&gt;we weren&amp;#39;t just building software for our customers, we were always trying
to exceed their expectations!&lt;/em&gt; This is really hard on every individual on the
team and so, we needed a rest...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Why am I writing about all this then?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My main motivation has always to help other people, see them grow and grow
myself in the process. At the same time though I am a person that loves a
certain lifestyle. I love nature and the mountains, I enjoy running and really
nice coffee ( &lt;em&gt;maybe I should start a coffee roaster&lt;/em&gt; ). I want to be able
to do all these things whenever I feel like doing them; I want to spend more
time in nature exploring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&quot;http://makersacademy.com&quot;&gt;Makers Academy&lt;/a&gt; I have an amazing job and
responsibility with an amazing team of friends. It&amp;#39;s amazing what we do and
how we are able to change the life of the students that come to the course.
It&amp;#39;s not really a job, it suits my lifestyle. Yes, sometimes it is very hard,
and frustrating, but at the end it pays of to see this amazing people, our
students, having accomplished what they have in such a short time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still there has always been this idea of &lt;a href=&quot;http://patheleven.com&quot;&gt;patheleven&lt;/a&gt;
nagging me in the back of my head. You might hear from it soon, or &lt;em&gt;maybe not
...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Two weeks</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2014/08/27/two-weeks/"/>
   <updated>2014-08-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2014/08/27/two-weeks</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;They say that it takes about 14 days to form an habit. Committing every day to a project is actually quite hard, we want to do this for the next 100 days...&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Introducing chronicler</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2014/08/26/chronicler/"/>
   <updated>2014-08-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2014/08/26/chronicler</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So &lt;a href=&quot;/2014/08/25/100-days/&quot;&gt;yesterday I announced&lt;/a&gt; the idea &lt;a href=&quot;http://roidriscoll.github.io&quot;&gt;Roi&lt;/a&gt; and me had about committing every day to &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I set up a new project, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ecomba/chronicler&quot;&gt;chronicler&lt;/a&gt; to start working on it for some time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ecomba/chronicler&quot;&gt;Chronicler&lt;/a&gt; is a blogging service that will focus on the content creation and ease of use. I want non-technical bloggers not to have to worry about anything but their content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code will be open source, but I will add a service as well for those who don&amp;#39;t want to deal with the technicalities of setting a chronicler instance up ( &lt;em&gt;big words... I haven&amp;#39;t even really started with the project and I am talking about these things already&lt;/em&gt; ).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wish me luck with it and if you like the idea ( &lt;em&gt;once you see a little more of code in the project repo&lt;/em&gt; ) maybe you can chip in and help?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>100 days</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2014/08/25/100-days/"/>
   <updated>2014-08-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2014/08/25/100-days</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this will not be finished in the first hundred days. 
Nor will it be finished in the first thousand days, nor in 
the life of this administration, nor even perhaps in 
our lifetime on this planet. But let us begin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John F. Kennedy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my friend &lt;a href=&quot;http://roidriscoll.github.io&quot;&gt;Roi&lt;/a&gt; and me have started this thing... a &lt;a href=&quot;http://roidriscoll.github.io/blog/2014/08/25/100-days/&quot;&gt;100 days&lt;/a&gt; of creating content, or rather a 100 days of pushing code to &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coding is a passion of mine, but recently I have been working mostly on private projects and repos, which is great, but we want to produce things that are useful for people as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a ton of projects and ideas that one can build to help, and I am going to start working on some.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am thinking about a blogging engine that I thought about a while ago, but never got to work on as I somehow had the idea of it being a commercial product ( &lt;em&gt;also I wanted to use it myself for blogging, maybe I will, maybe I will just create it and let others do it&lt;/em&gt; ). This might be a good starting project, I will see. &lt;strong&gt;The important part is working on something, &lt;em&gt;many different things&lt;/em&gt;, to create the habit&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wish us luck and, &lt;strong&gt;hey&lt;/strong&gt; if you have an idea that you don&amp;#39;t mind to be an &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_source&quot;&gt;open source project&lt;/a&gt;, just let us know! &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>tmux-conf</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2014/08/24/tmux/"/>
   <updated>2014-08-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2014/08/24/tmux</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Usually I keep &lt;em&gt;dot&lt;/em&gt; and configuration files somehow on &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt; so that I can retrieve them in case of a mayor disaster ( &lt;em&gt;laptop blowing up, etc&lt;/em&gt; ).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other day I was pairing with a friend. I decided I wanted to share with him my remote pairing configuration... &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WTF!!! WHERE DID IT GO?!?!?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not to long ago my trusted &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/macbook-air/&quot;&gt;MacBook Air&lt;/a&gt; stopped working and I changed it for a &lt;a href=&quot;http://makersacademy.com&quot;&gt;Makers Academy&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/macbook-pro/&quot;&gt;MackBook Pro&lt;/a&gt; ( &lt;em&gt;a really nice machine if you ask me&lt;/em&gt; ). Given that I am not working remotely at the moment I didn&amp;#39;t have any &lt;a href=&quot;http://tmux.sourceforge.net&quot;&gt;tmux&lt;/a&gt; or my trusted configurations setup... &lt;em&gt;a real bummer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I quickly installed it and went through it with him, but having learned the lesson, I added it to &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/ecomba&quot;&gt;my github&lt;/a&gt; for future reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are remotely interested in my &lt;a href=&quot;http://tmux.sourceforge.net&quot;&gt;tmux&lt;/a&gt; configuration you can take a look at it &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/ecomba/tmux-conf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Mushin no shin - 無心の心</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2014/08/23/mushin/"/>
   <updated>2014-08-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2014/08/23/mushin</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Hell is something you carry around with you. Not somewhere you go.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—Neil Gaiman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday we had a wonderful &lt;em&gt;Talks Night (tm)&lt;/em&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;http://makersacademy.com&quot;&gt;Makers Academy&lt;/a&gt;! If you haven&amp;#39;t ever been to a &lt;strong&gt;Makers Academy Talks Night&lt;/strong&gt;  and you happen to be a student at our academy, you definitely should!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;strong&gt;Makers Academy Talks Night&lt;/strong&gt; you will learn a lot of things that you possibly didn&amp;#39;t know about, like how to produce music, how to save money by batch-cooking, Venezuela, Singapore, women in tech, ... &lt;strong&gt;you name it&lt;/strong&gt; It is a really great evening and the kudos really go to all the students, but specially to those who had the courage to stand in front of everyone giving a talk!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to write a little about this concept, I have been talking about a little for the last five years or so, as I gave a talk about it during our &lt;strong&gt;Makers Academy Talks Night&lt;/strong&gt; yesterday; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/talks/mushin-no-shin&quot;&gt;Mushin no shin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your brain does many things to cope, specially when under perceived stress conditions (&lt;em&gt;learning in a bootcamp counts as such&lt;/em&gt;), it might default to &lt;strong&gt;fear&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;or rather anxiety&lt;/em&gt;), &lt;strong&gt;anger&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;ego&lt;/strong&gt;. These are all natural emotions that we all experience in our lifetimes (&lt;em&gt;sometimes even multiple times a day&lt;/em&gt;). The problem with all of them is that they will not help you in those situations that require your full attention. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your mind is troubled and there is a lot of chatter that does not allow you to react to the situation at hand as you are to busy inside your emotional state. &lt;em&gt;Mushin no shin&lt;/em&gt;, or the mind that is no mind is a state in which your mind is not fixed or busy with thought or emotion, but rather open to everything. It is an ideal mind state in which you can absorb knowledge at incredible speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is a difficult state of mind to achieve and to keep, but as everything we do, it&amp;#39;s not about how easy it is, but how much we invest in it for our own sake.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Dwelling in the future</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2014/01/02/dwelling/"/>
   <updated>2014-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2014/01/02/dwelling</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything we hear is an opinion, not a fact.
Everything we see is a perspective, not the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Marcus Aurelius&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another year has passed, and it has been a quite interesting year. A lot of things have happened in this past 12 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to write this post as a retrospection on what has been happening in this past year, but I feel like this would be &lt;em&gt;dwelling in the past&lt;/em&gt;, something I advocate not to do to anyone that asks me. So following my own advice I am going to just say what I do want to do in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;I want to spend more time exercising&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the end of last year I began to run again. This is a mayor achievement for me (&lt;em&gt;I need a badge for that!&lt;/em&gt;) as I haven&amp;#39;t exercised in ages before that. I have found that running gives me some peace of mind, similar as meditation does for a lot of people. I definitely want to keep on doing this and set time aside for it (&lt;em&gt;hopefully every day&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;I want to write more&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing is hard. You need a lot of alone time to be able to do this (&lt;em&gt;writers confinement&lt;/em&gt;). At times I have a lot of drive to write and it seems that I cannot stop doing it, but other times  no single word comes out of my hands. I want to do this more. This Christmas I set a little task for myself (&lt;em&gt;which I have been doing&lt;/em&gt;) of writing every morning some thoughts, an account of the past day, or just about anything that was on my mind. I hope that this new year I will be able to produce more writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;I want to write more software&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I actually write a ton of software. I code every day on different languages and things to satisfy my ever growing curiosity. What I feel though is that I want to release more products to the world. Not as a capital gain or to make any successful business out of them (although that would be welcome as well), but to actually produce something that people can use in their daily lives that will help them somehow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;I want to reach out more to my friends&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love my friends! They are all over the globe and meeting them is always linked with a trip to somewhere else. The problem with me is that I am not really good at communicating with the people I hold dear when they are not around. It&amp;#39;s so easy to fall into the daily &lt;em&gt;grind&lt;/em&gt; and forget to tell someone you appreciate that you are thinking about them. This year I am going to try to do that more and keep in contact with my friends (&lt;em&gt;If you are one of them and you are reading this, I am really sorry that I suck so much in keeping the contact alive&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;I want to loose and gain some habits&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year I spent a lot of time reading about habits and living a simpler lifestyle. This is something that resonates with me. I have been working on that over the past few years, and I want to continue doing that. Life is simple, we should keep our lifestyle simple as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than that I think that I will keep on helping as many people as I can (easy with &lt;a href=&quot;http://makersacademy.com&quot;&gt;my current line of work&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Happy 2014 to everyone out there!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Merry Christmas</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2013/12/24/merry-xmass/"/>
   <updated>2013-12-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2013/12/24/merry-xmass</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was about to open my email client and start sending Christmas emails to everyone I know. Then I thought that maybe I should first write this blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time of the year the lucky ones amongst us gather with family and loved ones to celebrate; some for religious reasons, others as an excuse to spend some days together once a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some amongst us, less lucky, with no place to go. For those of you, who have nowhere to go or no family, loved ones or friends to spend the night with I extend my love; &lt;strong&gt;you are in my thoughts tonight&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my friends close and far, my colleagues at work and people I have worked with during this past year &lt;strong&gt;I love you all!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Merry Christmas to you all!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;And now I am off to celebrate with my family...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>An uphill battle</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2013/12/14/uphill-battle/"/>
   <updated>2013-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2013/12/14/uphill-battle</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our doubts are traitors,
and make us lose the good we oft might win,
by fearing to attempt.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ William Shakespeare&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you push yourself out of your comfort zone you often confront yourself with your &lt;em&gt;resistance&lt;/em&gt;. It shouts at you and makes you doubt about your ability, your intelligence, your &lt;em&gt;self&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest fight for the learner it the fight with his inner self, the countless battles fought with &lt;em&gt;resistance&lt;/em&gt; in order to step outside your &lt;em&gt;comfort zone&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your &lt;em&gt;resistance&lt;/em&gt; is the devil on your shoulder telling you that you can never truly learn that hard new skill you want to acquire. It tells you that the hard work you are putting into learning does not matter. That the knowledge that is clamoring to leap out of you will always be restrained by social pressure, time, and the ringing words of all those who have laughed at your in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fight it, you are not alone, we all suffer this malady and we all fight everyday with it to get ourselves up on our feet yet again.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Why I teach at Makers Academy</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2013/11/10/why-makers/"/>
   <updated>2013-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2013/11/10/why-makers</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have been asked a couple of times now why I teach at &lt;a href=&quot;http://makersacademy.com&quot;&gt;Makers Academy&lt;/a&gt; instead of making &lt;em&gt;a lot of money&lt;/em&gt; with my skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could write about many reasons that this is so; &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/shadchnev&quot;&gt;being&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/startuprob&quot;&gt;part&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/JordanPoulton&quot;&gt;of&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/alexpeattie&quot;&gt;an&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/anitacanita&quot;&gt;awesome&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/rubenkostucki&quot;&gt;team&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/Jamedjo&quot;&gt;helps&lt;/a&gt;, but that is not the main reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last friday, at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://alumni.makersacademy.com/cohorts/august&quot;&gt;graduation&lt;/a&gt;, magic happened while having an inocent conversation with the mother of one of our graduates; a humbling moment; a compliment; an inspiring gesture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many different reasons that make teaching a fullfilling calling, but that conversation trumped everything so far:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 12 weeks you have achieved what I, as a mother, haven&amp;#39;t in a lifetime; thank you!
~ mom&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Use your imagination</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2013/10/27/use-your-imagination/"/>
   <updated>2013-10-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2013/10/27/use-your-imagination</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The true sign of intelligence is not knowledge but imagination. ~ Albert Einstein&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the hardest thing for a learner is to start being able to use his imagination in order to apply his knowledge. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we learn something new, we learn a way of doing something, a syntax. This information will not stick long in our heads if we don&amp;#39;t practice, practice, practice the newly acquired skill a lot while it is still fresh in our heads. Once we do though something interesting starts to happen. Our brain starts recognising patterns and weaving new ideas and ways we could accomplish the same thing or improve over it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A musician learns to play note by note a song. It sounds boring and lifeless, even if he hits every note perfectly well. But as he practices over and over he starts making that song his; a piece of his soul wanders into his instrument and the notes he is playing, art happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you learn something novell, go over what you have learned, a million times and over again, but then, let your imagination and your playfulness have a go at it and create new pathways and patterns around the acquired knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Agile & XP Basics</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2013/10/22/agile-xp/"/>
   <updated>2013-10-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2013/10/22/agile-xp</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I gave a little talk at &lt;a href=&quot;http://makersacademy.com&quot;&gt;Makers Academy&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;em&gt;the basics&lt;/em&gt; of agile and specially XP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find it on &lt;a href=&quot;http://speakerdeck.com&quot;&gt;Speaker Deck&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://speakerdeck.com/ecomba/agile-and-xp-basics&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Writing for the next developer</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2013/10/19/the-next-developer/"/>
   <updated>2013-10-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2013/10/19/the-next-developer</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The other day I was going through some code with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/shadchnev&quot;&gt;Evgeny&lt;/a&gt; and we had a discussion about the &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/954570/definition-of-clean-code&quot;&gt;cleanness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; of it. The code in question was by no means wrong or anything, but it &lt;em&gt;felt&lt;/em&gt; strange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you spend years in a profession you have an intuition about what can be done better and what feels wrong (&lt;em&gt;we usually call this &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Code_smell&quot;&gt;code smells&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyhow, let&amp;#39;s go back to the code in question, shall we?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine you have a piece of code that allows a person to rent a bike from a docking station (&lt;em&gt;in London we call these things &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barclays_Cycle_Hire&quot;&gt;Boris Bikes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;). The docking station would look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;class DockingStation
  def rent(bike)
    # something interesting happens here to return a bike
  end
end  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking closer at that piece of code we notice that the caller will have to know about the existance of a given bike inside that station for him to actually be able to rent the bike. Now that we have decided for this interface we have to provide a means for the caller to at least see the bikes in the docking station:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;class DockingStation
  def available_bikes
    # return collection of the bikes
    # in the station
  end
end  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you look at this from the point of view of a real life scenario, a person wanting to rent a bike will most definitely &lt;em&gt;choose&lt;/em&gt; his bike from the ones he can see on the station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, if you look at this problem from the point of view that a bike is stored in a database and will have to be pulled from the database in order for it to be rented it might look as it is perfectly OK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far so good... &lt;strong&gt;What&amp;#39;s my problem with this code then?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue I have with this approach is the amount of &lt;em&gt;knowledge&lt;/em&gt; the caller has to have about the inner representation of the docking station in order to rent &lt;em&gt;a bike&lt;/em&gt; from a docking station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most codebases are not build around the notion of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/User_experience_design&quot;&gt;user experience&lt;/a&gt; the next developer will have with the code we produce. How easy will it be to use? How much will we have to read in order to understand how to use this code? Will it make us happy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spend a lot of time thinking in those terms when I am coding, I am not only solving a problem, I am making conscious choices about how my code will be used and what you can expect from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#39;s look a a different approach to this problem; &lt;em&gt;renting a bike from a docking station&lt;/em&gt;. What the caller to the docking station ultimately wants to do is &lt;em&gt;renting a bike&lt;/em&gt;. He doesn&amp;#39;t want to deal with any specifics of the docking station, it&amp;#39;s not his responsiblilty:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;class DockingStation
  def rent_bike
    # do something to return an available bike
  end
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we have decided to include what was the argument to the method into the methods signature. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What have we achived here?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all we don&amp;#39;t need to pass in an argument to the method anymore, which makes the code simpler to use. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, by including what was the arguments name in the previous example in the method signature, we have now a method that &lt;a href=&quot;http://c2.com/cgi/wiki?IntentionRevealingNames&quot;&gt;reveals its intent&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally the caller no longer has to know &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; things are done inside the docking station; the inner structure is left to be the dockings stations responsability. This actually has many advantages as we can change that inner structure any time without affecting any code that uses our docking station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the most important lesson here is that we have made the life of the next developer easier; we have thought about what he will experience and feel while using our docking station. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&amp;#39;s your turn!&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Next time you are writing code think about what the next developer will feel and experience when interacting with your code.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>You cannot teach someone to code in n-weeks</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2013/10/18/cannot-teach/"/>
   <updated>2013-10-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2013/10/18/cannot-teach</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You read that right. Surprised? Challenged? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hear those words a lot from people not involved in helping people to learn how to code. It seems, to them, that what we are doing is something that cannot be accomplished; the human brain appears (&lt;em&gt;to them again&lt;/em&gt;) not to be capable of processing the sheer amount of information needed to become a developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having done this now for some while I could not disagree more with the title of this blogpost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have seen people developing skills that they did not have before on a weekly basis. Makers that only used their computers to entertain themselves suddenly are capable, within a few weeks (&lt;em&gt;three to be exact&lt;/em&gt;) to develop a domain model with objects interacting with each other, &lt;strong&gt;TEST FIRST!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, in the second week of learning how to code, I see people solving &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kata_(programming)&quot;&gt;coding katas&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;em&gt;like the &lt;a href=&quot;http://codingdojo.org/cgi-bin/wiki.pl?KataFizzBuzz&quot;&gt;FizzBuzz&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&quot;http://codingdojo.org/cgi-bin/wiki.pl?KataRomanNumerals&quot;&gt;Roman Numerals&lt;/a&gt; katas&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The human brain is capable of absorbing and processing huge amounts of information, we do that every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our challenge&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;finding and perfecting ways to tap into that potential in order to unleash the full learning capacity of the human brain&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>I am here</title>
   <link href="http://ecomba.pro/2013/10/17/i-am-here/"/>
   <updated>2013-10-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecomba.pro/2013/10/17/i-am-here</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We could learn a lot from crayons: some are sharp, 
some are pretty, some are dull, while others bright, 
some have weird names, but they have all learned to 
live in the same box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally I got my new blogging engine &lt;a href=&quot;http://ghost.org&quot;&gt;ghost&lt;/a&gt; up and 
running. I pretended to have a more &lt;em&gt;dramatic&lt;/em&gt; blog entry as my first one, 
but to be honest I am so excited about having this thing working and running 
after I have put in so much effort into it the last couple of days that I 
just needed to get something out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyhow, in the (&lt;em&gt;hopefully&lt;/em&gt; near) future I will post my ideas and thoughts 
about many software related (and unrelated) things...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wish me luck!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;E!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
