<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-01-18T10:22:21+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Enrique’s Musings</title><subtitle>Where I ponder about matters that pop into my headspace</subtitle><author><name>Enrique Comba Riepenhausen</name><email>hello@ecomba.pro</email></author><entry><title type="html">You cannot teach agility</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024-01-18/you-cannot-teach-agility" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="You cannot teach agility" /><published>2024-01-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-01-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024-01-18/you-cannot-teach-agility</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024-01-18/you-cannot-teach-agility"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>The secret of change is to focus all of your energy, not on fighting the old, but on building the new.</p>

  <p>~ Socrates</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Enrique Comba Riepenhausen</name><email>hello@ecomba.pro</email></author><category term="musings" /><category term="feedback" /><category term="coaching" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The secret of change is to focus all of your energy, not on fighting the old, but on building the new. ~ Socrates]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Practice and Preparation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023-12-28/practice-and-preparation" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Practice and Preparation" /><published>2023-12-28T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-12-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023-12-28/practice-and-preparation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023-12-28/practice-and-preparation"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>Agility requires practice and preparation.</p>

  <p>~ Joshua Kerievsky, <a href="https://joyofagility.com">Joy of Agility</a></p>
</blockquote>

<p>During my Christmas break, I am catching up with my reading, spending time reading the books I had set aside a while ago.</p>

<p>One of these books is <a href="https://joyofagility.com"><strong>Joy of Agility</strong></a> by <a href="https://www.industriallogic.com/people/joshua/">Joshua Kerievsky</a>. Having worked with Joshua a few years ago, I was thrilled to see him release this book after all the great work he’s been doing with <a href="https://modernagile.org">Modern Agile</a>.</p>

<p>I’m not going to talk about his book just yet (I’ll leave that review to when I finish reading it), but I wanted to highlight this quote as it resonated with me and the way I feel about agility.</p>

<p>Many people think that being agile is <em>just</em> following a set of practices.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>”If we follow these practices dictated by method <strong>S</strong> we will succeed in being <strong>A</strong>gile” (<em>or so the mantra goes</em>)</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Nothing could be further from the truth; agile is much more than a set of practices, but that’s for another day…</p>

<p>Being agile requires you to be good at what you do. You practice daily when your skills are needed to perform without overthinking about it.</p>

<p>Years ago, I was giving a class on <a href="https://www.industriallogic.com/blog/evolutionary-design/"><em>Evolutionary design</em></a> when one of the students told me that this way of working didn’t make much sense unless you know what you want at the end. I asked them what they meant by that. It turns out they didn’t trust their skills and intuition to take them on a journey to explore and code their design as it came along.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The lack of (<em>coding</em>) practice was a barrier to entry for this technique.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This happens with other methods, too; they feel awkward to start, and you will always feel challenged when trying them out without training.</p>

<p>Do you need help with any agile techniques you want to use at your workplace?</p>

<p><a href="mailto:info@ecomba.pro?subject=Help me with agile">Shoot me an email</a>, and we can discuss how I can help you and your team become more agile!</p>]]></content><author><name>Enrique Comba Riepenhausen</name><email>hello@ecomba.pro</email></author><category term="agile" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Agility requires practice and preparation. ~ Joshua Kerievsky, Joy of Agility]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Christmas</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023-12-24/christmas" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Christmas" /><published>2023-12-24T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-12-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023-12-24/christmas</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023-12-24/christmas"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>Christmas, children, is not a date. It is a state of mind.</p>

  <p>~ Mary Ellen Chase</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This is a strange time for me, especially this year. During Christmas time, people in the West celebrate some religious dates most of us don’t believe in. And yet, it’s somewhat magical; we come together, sit at a table and enjoy our company.</p>

<p>When I was a kid, the 24th of December was magical. We, the kids, would decorate the tree while my mother would spend almost all day in the kitchen preparing cookies and dinner for the evening.</p>

<p>Then, when the time was right, in the evening, we would be playing in my sisters’ room (<em>it was the furthest from the living room</em>). My mother would take the presents from their hiding place and put them under the tree while we played. Then she would play the Christmas bells from the Austrian Choir on our stereo in the living room at full pelt, and, we kids would run, laughing to the living room finding the tree and living room lit up, the smell of pine in the air. It was a magical moment for us, in which Santa had become real and had left presents for us.</p>

<p><strong>I love the memories of that time.</strong></p>

<p>And yet, I haven’t been able to recreate this for future generations in my adult life. Life has taken me on so many adventures (far and wide) and never allowed me to create that magical moment, so I eventually stopped celebrating it.</p>

<p>This year, I feel even less inclined to celebrate (<em>is that even possible?</em>), yet some personal circumstances have given me a little stab to make tonight special for someones who deserve a magical moment in their lives.</p>

<p>🎄<strong>Merry Christmas to you all!</strong> 🎄</p>]]></content><author><name>Enrique Comba Riepenhausen</name><email>hello@ecomba.pro</email></author><category term="holidays" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Christmas, children, is not a date. It is a state of mind. ~ Mary Ellen Chase]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Preparation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023-12-19/preparation" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Preparation" /><published>2023-12-19T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-12-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023-12-19/preparation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023-12-19/preparation"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>By failing to prepare, you are preparing to fail.</p>

  <p>~ Benjamin Franklin</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I’m working on preparing some courses for 2024. While doing so, I’m also looking at what’s available in the market.</p>

<p>Most courses lack a thorough syllabus or the amount of time needed to absorb the knowledge to be prepared for the task the course is setting (or equipping) you to do. Some of them offer hands-on training, but many are just classroom-type classes.</p>

<p>The first course I’ll be releasing (<em>hopefully soon</em>) is directed to <em>agile coaches</em> who are either about to start or with just a little time under their belts and want to improve their skills.</p>

<p>It won’t give you a world-renowned certificate (<em>although I can create a certificate for you if you so desire</em>), but it will prepare you for the task at hand.</p>

<p>One thing I’m also toying with is the availability of myself after you’ve completed the course. Many times, when we learn a new skill, once we’ve learned it, we are left alone to deal with our newly acquired knowledge; I want to change that (<em>not sure how I will make that happen yet though</em>)!</p>

<p>If you are interested in knowing more, you have two options.</p>

<p>You can wait and head over to <a href="https://ecomba.pro/courses">my website</a>
, or you can <a href="mailto:info@ecomba.pro?subject=Tell me more about your courses">shoot me an email and ask me directly</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Enrique Comba Riepenhausen</name><email>hello@ecomba.pro</email></author><category term="courses" /><category term="agile" /><category term="coaching" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[By failing to prepare, you are preparing to fail. ~ Benjamin Franklin]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Agile Theatre</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023-12-18/agile-theatre" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Agile Theatre" /><published>2023-12-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-12-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023-12-18/agile-theatre</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023-12-18/agile-theatre"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>Your values create your internal compass that can navigate how you make decisions in your life.</p>

  <p>~ Roy T. Bennett</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Many companies these days claim to “<em>be agile</em>”; the reason is pretty simple: they have adopted some of the practices defined long ago in the “<em>agile manifesto</em>”.</p>

<p>The funny thing about this is that the practices are the <strong>easiest</strong> part of “<em>being agile</em>”.</p>

<p>Practices help to be agile; they are little crutches you use to acclimate to the new shift in perspective. The real benefit of agility is, interestingly enough, embedded in part in the very word: “<strong>agile</strong>”.</p>

<p>The values a company and its people adhere to dictate directly how adaptable to change they are or, controversially, how calcified they’ve become.</p>

<p>Are you process-heavy? Do you follow the agile theatre, but somehow, you aren’t very agile as a whole?</p>

<p><a href="https://meetings-eu1.hubspot.com/enrique-comba-riepenhausen">Let’s talk</a> about your challenges; I know I can help you figure this out.</p>]]></content><author><name>Enrique Comba Riepenhausen</name><email>hello@ecomba.pro</email></author><category term="agility" /><category term="development" /><category term="values" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Your values create your internal compass that can navigate how you make decisions in your life. ~ Roy T. Bennett]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What went wrong?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023-12-15/what-went-wrong" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What went wrong?" /><published>2023-12-15T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-12-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023-12-15/what-went-wrong</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023-12-15/what-went-wrong"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>The past cannot be regained, although we can learn from it; the future is not yet ours even though we must plan for it… Time is now. We have only today.</p>

  <p>~ Charles Hummell</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Do you remember when you first came into contact with agile software development?</p>

<p>For me, it was somewhat in the late 90’s. I remember that time fondly. We worked in a high-stakes environment, creating software for Germany’s first online insurance company. We were experiencing high pressure, and the stakes for our clients for such a disruptive product were even higher.</p>

<p>As one of the technical leads in our team, I was feeling the pressure; it was almost unbearable; something had to change.</p>

<p>That’s when I came across the <a href="http://c2.com">c2 wiki</a>. I spent so much time absorbing the knowledge embedded in those pages; it changed me.</p>

<p>Agile has always meant to be a change in your inner values, a joyful way of working, and ultimately focusing primarily on shipping software that matters.</p>

<p>Over the last decade(s), there has been a tendency to focus on rituals and team topology practices, which, if dissected, don’t add to the company’s bottom line in any meaningful way.</p>

<p>Are you overcomplicating your processes and teams? Is your software being shipped consistently?</p>

<p><a href="https://meetings-eu1.hubspot.com/enrique-comba-riepenhausen">Let’s talk</a> about your challenges; I know I can help you untangle the mess you’ve gotten into.</p>]]></content><author><name>Enrique Comba Riepenhausen</name><email>hello@ecomba.pro</email></author><category term="agile" /><category term="work" /><category term="software-development" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The past cannot be regained, although we can learn from it; the future is not yet ours even though we must plan for it… Time is now. We have only today. ~ Charles Hummell]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Coaching</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023-12-14/coaching" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coaching" /><published>2023-12-14T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-12-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023-12-14/coaching</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023-12-14/coaching"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>The only person you are destined to become is the person you decide to be.</p>

  <p>~ Ralph Waldo Emerson</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I had a lovely catch-up with an old friend and fellow coach yesterday. We shared our life stories and what we’ve been up to up until now.</p>

<p><strong>Inevitably, we talked about our work as coaches.</strong></p>

<p>One thing that stood out for me is how there is a belief, in some communities and companies, that a coach is some tree-hugging, hippy person (<em>I have in no way or form anything against people focusing on these parts of the human experience</em>) focusing on intangibles that are way off the business’s primary focus.</p>

<p>Coaching a business, a team, or a person in a working environment has (<em>or, at the very minimum, should have</em>) measurable outcomes which will improve some key operating strategy for the company (<em>what, in detail, depends on the engagement</em>). Anything else is just a <em>” feel-good experience”</em> for the team (there is value in that too).</p>

<p><strong>What kind of coach do you need?</strong></p>

<p><strong>P.S.</strong>: <em>If you are currently coaching teams and would like to be coached to become better at what you do, you can always <a href="https://meetings-eu1.hubspot.com/enrique-comba-riepenhausen">reach out to me</a>, and we’ll figure something out</em>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Enrique Comba Riepenhausen</name><email>hello@ecomba.pro</email></author><category term="coaching" /><category term="work" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The only person you are destined to become is the person you decide to be. ~ Ralph Waldo Emerson]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Anga!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023-12-13/anga" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Anga!" /><published>2023-12-13T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-12-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023-12-13/anga</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023-12-13/anga"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>Speak when you are angry, and you will make the best speech you will ever regret.</p>

  <p>~ Ambrose Bierce</p>
</blockquote>

<p>You read that title right, “<em>Anga!</em>”. It reminded me of a short video clip from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steve_Harvey">Steve Harvey</a>, where he mocked someone for pronouncing the word “anger” as “anga”.</p>

<p>Recently, a business partner of mine wrote an email to a renowned person in some industry, asking them for advice.</p>

<p>Interestingly enough, he received an answer that differed from what he expected. The reply was full of anger and frustration, to the point my business partner replied apologising for having caused any distress (<em>he still did not know where this was coming from</em>) and explaining more about what he was after.</p>

<p>This event prompted a conversation between us partners.</p>

<p>Here is my take on replying to unsolicited emails:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Don’t reply in anger (<em>even if the mail made you angry for some unknown reason</em>).</li>
  <li>Instead, wait till it passes or don’t reply at all.</li>
  <li>Always be polite.</li>
  <li>If you are not interested in what the other person is offering, let them know (<em>politely</em>).</li>
  <li>It’s always better to reply than to keep silent (<em>you know how you feel when someone doesn’t answer your emails, calls, messages, etc.</em>).</li>
</ul>

<p>If you wonder how the story with the angry mailer ended, he apologised (<em>in his way</em>) and clarified where he was coming from… which could be a different blog post, so I’m leaving that for tomorrow…</p>]]></content><author><name>Enrique Comba Riepenhausen</name><email>hello@ecomba.pro</email></author><category term="musings" /><category term="emotions" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Speak when you are angry, and you will make the best speech you will ever regret. ~ Ambrose Bierce]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A better team</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023-12-12/a-better-team" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A better team" /><published>2023-12-12T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-12-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023-12-12/a-better-team</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023-12-12/a-better-team"><![CDATA[<p>Over the last ten years (<em>way more, but who’s counting 😅</em>), I’ve been thinking about a tool to help agile coaches and teams without a coach.</p>

<p>I had this problem a while ago when I started coaching and got my first few clients; <em>“How do I keep organised?”</em>, <em>“How do I share insights or activities with the teams?”</em></p>

<p>I always ended up using a mixture of different tools to keep myself organised. The problem with that (<em>at least for me</em>) is that I end up misplacing important information, missing key insights (<em>or spending too much time studying my notes</em>), making me work harder than I could.</p>

<p>A few years back, <a href="https://twitter.com/sbastn">Sebastian Hermida</a> created an excellent (and free) tool based on <a href="http://www.jamesshore.com">James Shores’</a> “Agile Self Assessment Quiz” (from the first edition of his book “<a href="http://www.jamesshore.com/v2/books/aoad2">The Art of Agile Software Development</a>”).</p>

<p>Since then, though, it’s offline 😞.</p>

<p>Talking to Sebastian (<em>this is now about three years ago</em>), I asked him if I could use the name of the original domain he used as I wanted to create tools around agile coaching and helping teams get coaching. He gave me the green light to do whatever I liked with that domain.</p>

<p>So, now we are at the end of 2023, and my tool isn’t there yet, but I’ve got some renewed strength, and I’m seriously thinking of making this happen and scratching that old itch I have.</p>

<p><strong>Are you an agile coach?</strong> <strong>Are you in a team that needs coaching?</strong></p>

<h3 id="i-would-love-to-hear-from-you-and-see-your-needs-for-your-coaching-business-or-team">I would love to hear from you and see your needs for your coaching business or team!</h3>

<p><strong><a href="https://meetings-eu1.hubspot.com/enrique-comba-riepenhausen">Let’s talk!</a></strong></p>]]></content><author><name>Enrique Comba Riepenhausen</name><email>hello@ecomba.pro</email></author><category term="ideas" /><category term="coaching" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the last ten years (way more, but who’s counting 😅), I’ve been thinking about a tool to help agile coaches and teams without a coach.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Creativity</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023-12-11/creativity" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Creativity" /><published>2023-12-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-12-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023-12-11/creativity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023-12-11/creativity"><![CDATA[<p>While having coffee again this morning, I came across this image (from <em>@WisdomMadeEasy</em>).</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/creativity.jpeg" alt="Creativity" /></p>

<p>It speaks volumes!</p>

<p>When we try to cage creativity into a closed environment (<em>like in a meeting-like setting</em>), it hardly ever flows.
Then, we go for a walk in a park by the side of a brook, our brain seemingly tapping into a limitless source 
of it.</p>

<p>Maybe next time you want to schedule a meeting to “<em>be creative together</em>” instead of meeting, let your people go 
for an extended walk and see what they’ve come up with afterwards!</p>]]></content><author><name>Enrique Comba Riepenhausen</name><email>hello@ecomba.pro</email></author><category term="creativity" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[While having coffee again this morning, I came across this image (from @WisdomMadeEasy).]]></summary></entry></feed>